# **Muddassir Nazir**

E 92/1, Fourth Floor, St. 6, Shaheen Bagh • Jamia Nagar, Okhla, New Delhi • 110025 **Phone:** +91-7597922367 • **Email:** muddassirnazir@protonmail.ch • **Website:** muddassirnazir.github.io

# **Objective**

I am a Computer Science Engineer, and want to use my experience and skills to perform system administration tasks and IT infrastructure management and enhance my knowledge for personal and organizational goals in a reputed organization that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.

# **Professional Experience**

May 2015 - Present	ZNetlive Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Jaipur
	Linux System Administrator (L1)

October 2013 – March 2014 GRRAS Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Jaipur

Linux System Administrator (Intern)

#### **Technical Skills**

- Linux System Administration: Apache Web Server, SSH Security, Bind DNS, Mail Server (Sendmail, Postfix, Exim), User Management, NFS, SAMBA, SELinux, iptables, Disk Usage Management, LVM, Process Management, Task Scheduling and Automation, Service Monitoring and Management and Troubleshooting.
- Bash Shell Scripting
- **Virtualization:** VMWare Workstation, Oracle Virtual Box.
- Web Hosting: cPanel, WHM Administration, FTP, Log Analysis
- Hands on with Red Hat & Derivatives (CentOS, Fedora), Debian Family (Ubuntu, Mint) & OpenSuse.
- GlusterFS Storage configuration and administration.
- Exposure to Github, Cloud Computing, OpenStack, Oracle Solaris 11.

#### Education

2011 – 2015 Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering
Vivekananda Institute of Technology (East), Jaipur
Graduated – May 2015

## **Certifications**

- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (Certification Id. 130-179-682)
- Red Hat Certified Engineer (Certification Id. 130-179-682)
- Red Hat Certified OpenStack Administrator (Certification Id. 130-179-682)
- Red Hat Certificate of Expertise in Hybrid Cloud Storage (Certification Id. 130-179-682)
- CloudU Certificate from RackSpace (<a href="http://goo.gl/o7DnJU">http://goo.gl/o7DnJU</a>)
- cPanel Certification L1: Base (Certification Id. 82831301291441969659)

## **Web Info**

Other Email: mnstalemate@hotmail.com

Skype: mnstalemate

LinkedIn: in.linkedin.com/in/muddassirnazir

Google Plus: <a href="https://plus.google.com/+MuddassirNazir">https://plus.google.com/+MuddassirNazir</a>

## **Extra-Curricular Activities**

- Student Organizer at Microsoft Cloud Roadshow 2015, Jaipur
- Student Organizer at Microsoft Tech Vista 2014, Jaipur.
- Organized College Events (2012-2015).
- Secured 3<sup>rd</sup> Rank in National Science Talent Search Exam (2008).
- Participating in Educational Seminars and Conferences since 2005.
- Won Bronze Medal at National Level in Philately Competition (2001).
- Motivating and Helping Computer Science Graduates in choosing Careers.